John Isom

■ john@johnisom.dev **②** johnisom.dev **⑤** johnisom **in** john-isom

Generalist Software Engineer with rich experience working with and building microservice architectures with Node.js, Ruby, Kafka, C#/ASP.NET Core, React.js and more. I do my best work and love working on the backend, solving the unique problems there.

Professional Experience

Fullstack Software Engineer, *DeepL*

Feb 2024 – present

- Led MVP for sharing glossaries, collaborating with stakeholders and very closely with product. On track to deliver feature well ahead of roadmap, providing a very valuable and highly-requested feature.
- Worked closely with Senior and Principal Engineers, delivering Glossary Generator under tight deadlines.
- Did my best to be a good colleague, lending my specific experience cross-team when possible, pushing forward new topics for discussion, setting up team rituals and fostering a close, collaborative environment.

Software Engineer, *Prime Trust*

Jan 2022 – Aug 2023

- Reduced monthly operating costs by \$120k by integrating a new ledger system with millions of transactions and by improving business logic.
- Researched and ran learning sessions for Docker & Docker Compose and Kafka.
- Set up Kafka and set up data pipelines between multiple Ruby and Typescript services.
- Dockerified the monolith and pioneered the use of Docker in all future services.
- Created brand-new TypeScript Node.js services with express.js and Nest.js, automating manual processes to be more accurate and efficient.
- Worked with Staff Engineers to set up inter-service authentication.
- Onboarded and mentored a new teammate, ran meetings, and created an optional and successful biweekly team social hour.

Software Development Engineer III, *GoDaddy*

Nov 2020 – Jan 2022

- Led the adoption of a new attachment backend in our Rails app, managing and executing the seamless migration of 20 million file attachments with no downtime or performance issues using multi-threading.
- Created a new column in a database table with 118 million+ records and backfilled the values with minimal downtime.
- Spearheaded migrating a massive monolithic Rails app from Rails $5 \rightarrow 6$.
- Designed and added drop-in encryption for sensitive fields in our database with full backward compatibility and no downtime.

Co-Creator & Software Engineer, *Maestro Framework*

Jul 2020 – Oct 2020

Open-source, easy-to-use framework for quickly bootstrapping serverless orchestration workflows.

- Created a framework that is over 60x faster to deploy than the fastest competitor (AWS SAM).
- Co-authored a detailed case study that explores the area of serverless orchestration, existing solutions in the problem space, and the process of creating Maestro (https://maestro-framework.github.io/ ☑).

Languages and Technologies

Languages — JavaScript (ES5 & ES6+) | TypeScript | Ruby | C# | SQL, **Frameworks** — Rails | express.js | Next.js | ASP.NET | Roda; Sequel (Ruby), **Cloud** — AWS Step Functions; S3; Lambda; EC2 | Kafka; RabbitMQ | Docker & Docker Compose, **Other** — Linux | Git; GitHub; GitHub actions | Postgres; Ceph; Cassandra

Education

Western Governors University,

2021 - 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science